Guide to the Andrea White Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Andrea White Papers
1993-2010
2004-2010
02/2011-010
White, Andrea, 1953-
1.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection includes speeches, written works, as well as DVDs and photo CDs that document civic and professional life of Andrea White, former First Lady of Houston, housed in one box and comprised of three series.
Biographical Information:
Andrea White, the wife of former Houston Mayor Bill White, was first lady of Houston, TX from 2004 to 2010. Andrea, a lawyer, civic leader, and author, was born in Baton Rouge, Louisiana to parents Arthur and Patsi Ferguson. She and her family later moved to Houston, where she attended Memorial High School before going on to receive both undergraduate and law degrees at The University of Texas at Austin.
As is evident from her writings and speeches, Andrea was a reluctant political spouse who suffered (at first) from a high level of “stage fright.” Now an experienced public speaker and lecturer, Andrea fondly remembers when she once was called upon by her pastor to lead the congregation in song and was so frightened that the only “tune she could recall was Happy Birthday.”
Andrea is the author of eight books spanning 1993 to 2010 in the young adult genre. Her works are featured in the Texas Bluebonnet list as well as state reading lists across the nation. Andrea’s writings have also garnered her the Golden Spur Award, issued by the Texas State Reading Association.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Books; Clippings (information artifacts); Compact discs; Correspondence; Manuscripts (document genre); Typescripts
Personal Name:
White, Andrea, 1953-
Topical Term:
Authors -- 20th century; Authors, American -- 20th century; Children’s authors; Politicians’ spouses -- Texas -- Houston; Women in public life -- Texas -- Houston
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes speeches, written works, as well as DVDs and photo CDs that document civic and professional life of Andrea White, former First Lady of Houston, housed in one box and comprised of three series.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Detailed List of Contents
- Speeches, id123908
  Scope and Contents
  This series is comprised of speeches and presentations White delivered to various civic and volunteer groups between 2007 and 2010. Included are the original stump speeches she gave while her husband, Bill White, was a participant in the 2010 Texas gubernatorial race.
  - Draft Speech, 2007; id123918 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Speeches: “Women in Government” and “Brookwood Community”, 2008; id123919 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Speeches, 2009; id123920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Speeches, 2009-2010; id123921 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Texas Library Association presentation, 2009; id123922 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Reading from Radiant Gir l, undated; id123923 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photo CD of Speech at the LBJ Moral Courage Award Dinner, May, 2011; id123924 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Speech by Andrea campaigning for Bill in the Texas gubernatorial race, 2010; id123925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Published Works, id123909
  This series documents the development of Andrea White’s popular young adult fiction books. Included are translations of her works, Window Boy, and Surviving Antarctica, in Hungarian, Simplified Chinese, and Greek.
  - Radiant Girl, id123911
    - Correspondence, 2005; id123927 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Chernobyl background information (1 of 4), 2005; id123928 (Box 1, Folder 10-13)
    - Chernobyl background information (2 of 4), 2005-2007; id123929 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Chernobyl background information (3 of 4), 2009; id123930 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Chernobyl background information (4 of 4), 2009; id123931 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Draft, pages 2-39, undated; id123932 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Draft, pages 40-92, undated; id123933 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Draft, pages 93-149, undated; id123934 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Draft, pages 150-211, undated; id123935 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Quotes pasted on construction paper, undated; id123936 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Prepared reading, undated; id123937 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Radiant Girl and “Rita Monster” PowerPoint presentations on CD, undated; id123938 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Surviving Antarctica, id123912
    - Correspondence and collage, 2005; id123940 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - No Child’s Game: Binder containing research for the book, undated; id123941 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Hungarian translation, 2005; id123942 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      This book is available in UH Libraries Special Collections; call number PZ7.W58177 Su4 2005.
    - Greek translation, 2005; id123943 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      This book is available in UH Libraries Special Collections; call number PZ7.W58177 Su3 2005.
  - Windows on The World, id123913
    - Draft, pages 1-109, undated; id123945 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Draft, pages 110-199, undated; id123946 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Draft, pages 200-244, undated; id123947 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Newest Recruit, id123914
    - Edits by L. Smith, 2007; id123950 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Edits and correspondence by “JCC", undated; id123951 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Window Boy, id123915
    - Research notes, undated; id123953 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Glow Worms (original title for Window Boy) Correspondence and notes, 2007; id123954 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Simplified Chinese translation, 2010; id123955 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      This book is available in UH Libraries Special Collections; call number PZ7.W58177 Wi2 2010.
    - Three DVD’s: “An Introduction to Window Boy” by Andrea White, undated; id130115 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Thoughts on Being a Political Spouse, id123916
    - P.S., 2009; id123957 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      This book is available in UH Libraries Special Collections; call number F394.H853 W48 2009.
- Various Materials, id123910
  This series contains miscellaneous written works collected by Andrea White.
  - Works documenting the 1993 New York City World Trade Center bombing (1 of 3), 2007; id123959 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Works documenting the 1993 New York City World Trade Center bombing (2 of 3), 2007; id123960 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Works documenting the 1993 New York City World Trade Center bombing (3 of 3), undated; id123961 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Children’s cards, undated; id123962 (Box 1, Folder 38)